[theme song playing]
♪ Take a little walk
To the edge of town ♪
♪ And go across the tracks ♪
♪ Where the viaduct looms ♪
♪ Like a bird of doom ♪
♪ As it shifts and cracks ♪
♪ Where secrets lie
In the border fires ♪
♪ In the humming wires ♪
♪ Hey man, you know ♪
♪ You're never coming back ♪
♪ Past the square
Past the bridge ♪
♪ Past the mills
Past the stacks ♪
♪ On a gathering storm comes ♪
♪ A tall handsome man ♪
♪ In a dusty black coat with ♪
♪ A red right hand ♪
[Nutley] Your brothers came to my house.
They said the Peaky Blinders
had business with me.
[Tommy] You're not afraid of me.
So,
what is it you want
from a simple working man?
Fear.
[thunder rumbling]
Poor Mr. Nutley drank too much.
He went for a piss on the train tracks
that run behind the factory.
Train came.
They found his body in Saltley
broken into bits.
I know what you do.
Tell me what you want.
There.
The lot's complete warehouse.
Bays four, five and six.
You have the keys?
Yes, I have keys.
What's in bay four?
Completed type 40s and type 21s
waiting for the paint shop.
Bay five?
-[Nutley] Paint shop and parts.
-Uh-huh.
So, it's bay six.
What is?
[inhales sharply]
Give me the keys to bay six.
It's just old stock in storage.
[sighs]
[keys jangling]
For your trouble.
Give it to your charity.
I'm only doing this
for the safety of my family.
[rock music playing]
[grunts]
[sighs]
[sniffs]
[Hughes] So, will it be just boys in your
charitable institution or girls as well?
Both.
You must divide them.
You know how the little creatures can get.
Where are your people?
You said they'd be here by 5:00.
[Hughes] They are a law unto themselves.
You can never quite grasp who they are.
Like gripping wet soap.
I've done my research.
[Hughes mutters]
Perhaps you know them
as the, uh, Economic League.
Only once did I get a letter from them
headed "The Vigilance Committee."
Which tips the hand a little.
[clicks tongue] No.
The name I've heard is Section D.
-[pouring drink]
-That's what Special Branch calls them.
Businessmen, MPs, army officers.
[exhales]
[Hughes] Yes, it will be fun to bring
such men to a Gypsy scrapyard.
[scoffs]
You asked for privacy.
Since the election, the government
has decided that we are the enemy.
When all we're trying to do
is save the country from revolution.
Are you political, Mr. Shelby?
Because these Odd Fellows believe
that the time is coming soon
when everyone must choose a side.
Are your people coming
or are they not coming?
Mr. Shelby, you will learn that
these men are far too grand
for the clock to govern them.
You'll get used to meeting
in the small hours of the morning.
They're like monks.
So, when is your
charitable institute opening?
[exhales] When I fucking say.
Well, I'll stop by from time to time
to hear confession
from the little creatures.
You'll meet Mr. Patrick Jarvis, MP.
He'll probably want to become a trustee.
It's just his thing, to drop by
in the evenings after a few drinks.
We'll make it a formal arrangement
as part of the bigger deal between us.
-I will have an office there.
-[clearing throat]
[Tommy sniffles]
[spits]
Ah!
My God.
Some devil gets into you, doesn't it, boy?
Mr. Shelby,
if I want to play the squire in
your place of false charity, then I will.
Ambition for respectability
doesn't make you a saint.
Am I wrong?
[bell tolling]
Oh, Lord. That's 6:00, is it?
Well, I wish you a good day.
Where the fuck are you going?
Did I not make it clear?
They said if they weren't here
by morning prayers
then the meeting has been canceled.
Perhaps Mr. Jarvis has been held up
at the House of Commons.
Perhaps Admiral Hall's been held up
at the House of Lords.
Am I impressing you?
Or perhaps they have decided
they don't care for doing business
with Gypsies in scrap metal yards
which would be a poor outcome for you.
You give them my message from me, Priest.
You tell them I've been to the factories
and the armored vehicles
are in good condition.
[Hughes] How many?
Twenty-seven.
And the foreman is ours.
This is someone you'll meet.
Today, at the Ritz.
I have meetings today.
You have one meeting, this one.
In London.
So, you'd best catch the milk train.
[violin playing]
[birds chirping]
Cold.
My apologies, sir.
And how many times
I asked you to tell them
about sending us the servant's crockery.
[butler] I have no control
over the choice of service, sir.
Hmm, and what about yesterday's eggs
and last year's fish
and last century's tea leaves
in a cracked pot.
Sir, I have a list of today's social
engagements, if you'd like to hear them.
Oh, are we in a rush today?
-I have duties at the main house, sir.
-Mmm.
[butler] Luncheon at The Ritz
with Duke Michail Michailovich.
[Leon, in Russian]
He is such a bore.
Canceled.
-[in English] What reason?
-[butler] He says he is unwell, sir.
You are due to have tea at 3:00
with Prince Sevlod Ianovich
and Lady Mary Lewington, sir.
Mmm! Good.
I miss out on the bore
and meet the beauty.
However, in the absence of the Duke,
the, uh, Prince and the Lady,
too have canceled, sir.
Other than that,
your day is, uh, your own.
You do have one business appointment
to discuss automobiles
with a Mr. Thomas Shelby, sir.
[horse whinnying]
["DNA" playing]
♪ We will not be moved by it ♪
You asked for a meeting out in the open,
fresh air and the fine aroma of shit.
"Neutral ground," you said.
[Vicente] This is hardly neutral ground.
Well, it's what you've got.
So, por favor,
sit down.
-[Vicente] Where is Thomas?
-He got called away.
He'd said he'd be here.
[Arthur] Yeah, he is busy.
And I just told you he got called away.
What do you want?
There has been a peace
between the Peaky Blinders and
the Changretta family for two years now...
Do you want some tea or not?
Here, Finn, pour the Italians
some English tea. Go on.
We don't want fucking tea.
We want an explanation.
Well, I'll have fucking tea.
Explanation for what?
The Little Venice Restaurant
on Forge Street was burnt down...
No. No. Couldn't have been us,
we was at a wedding.
You burnt it down to stop my son
being at that same wedding.
He wasn't missed.
[laughs]
[chuckles]
You are such big boys now.
But once you borrowed clothes from us
to look like men.
-How's the tea, Arthur? Is it...
-[splashes]
It's cold.
Please tell Tommy
that we pay him
whatever he asks us to pay.
We stay out of the city
and off the tracks.
But you tell him from me
that my son will walk
with any woman in this city.
Any woman he chooses.
Even if that woman works for the emperor,
Thomas Shelby.
My son is in love...
[John snorts]
[John chuckling] Sorry. Do excuse me.
[sniffs] Carry on.
[Vicente] And if he wishes,
he will walk with the woman he loves.
Okay.
You know...
It would be hard for your son
to walk anywhere
with a bullet in each knee, wouldn't it.
Too much.
You said too much, my friend.
Sabini says, "Suck and swallow." But no.
Too much.
I spit. [spits]
[Vicente speaking Italian]
[John] Oh. Okay. A bit strong.
-[laughs] Fucking hell.
-Isiah.
Put two extra men on our pubs in Nechells.
What are you talking about, Arthur?
We're not scared of
fucking Eyeties anymore.
Don't tell Tommy about the chair
and clean this fucking shit up.
We're not scared of fucking wops!
[grumbles] All right, John.
Arthur!
[Tommy] Hello, Ada.
[Ada] Tommy Shelby? In a library?
[Tommy] I need to borrow a book
about the Russian Revolution.
[Ada] Have you got a new wharf
at Maida Vale now?
[Tommy] I've got a new wharf
everywhere now.
[Ada] Sometimes, I see our trucks
driving past.
[Tommy] "Our" trucks?
Shelby trucks.
Why the interest?
Eh, I just want to broaden my mind.
Well, this is a list of the bastards
who ran away.
And this is written from the point of view
of the peoples' struggle.
Uh-huh.
[Ada] There was a Russian at your wedding.
He wouldn't tell me
how come he got invited.
Well, sometimes,
exiled Russian aristocrats get invited
to social occasions to add a bit of class.
Is that why he was there?
Why do you want to know?
He was nice.
Maybe I'd like to see him again.
Would that be possible?
No. That would not be possible.
What business do you have
with the Russians, Tommy?
Can I rip this page out?
No, you cannot rip that page out.
-Property of the people.
-[sighing]
Tommy, when Arthur took the Russian away,
he had his killing pistol
under his jacket.
And then Johnny lit a fire in the woods.
You want all the details
because you're bored, Ada.
You used to chase rats
with a revolver, Ada.
-[people shushing]
-[softly] For fuck's sake.
I might just have a job for you after all.
[sighs]
[rock music playing]
[indistinct conversations]
Did we run Kempton yesterday or not?
Danny Lee got drunk.
Instead of injecting the horses
with cocaine,
he decided to share it with his cousins.
[sighs] Jesus Christ.
He's your brother-in-law.
Tell Esme to speak to him about it.
Look. Before I start...
I don't want you to do anything
about this.
About what?
Vicente Changretta's son.
-The one Lizzie was stepping out with--
-What, Angel?
He's no bigger
than twopence worth of change.
Well, he heard you threatened him
directly to shoot him in the knees.
And now he's going around Nechells
telling everybody he's going to kill you.
This is Lizzie's fault to start with,
Tommy's for leaving it up to you.
What are you talking about?
We run London.
We run the north,
we run the whole fucking country.
What do we care about
some fucking Nechells Green Eyeties?
We don't need to be getting involved
in all these little piss pots.
What does Arthur say?
That's why I'm here and not him.
If he said it, there'd be a fight.
He says,
"Apologize."
[sniffs]
He fucking said what?
[Polly] We own the city.
But we don't need to rub
everybody's noses in it.
If the old man decides to make a stand,
he might get Sabini feeling sentimental...
[John] Sabini's done.
They're all done.
And they all pay up.
But we don't want rebellions.
[sighs]
What does, um, Tommy say?
Tommy's busy. He left me in charge.
And what do you say?
-Compromise.
-Mmm-hmm.
I've asked Lizzie to do it for you.
She's going to meet him,
break up with him for good,
apologize for any inconvenience,
say it was all her fault...
-For fuck's sake!
-[clattering]
[hesitates] You know what all this is?
This is Arthur's fucking missus.
Turn the other fucking cheek?
We'll be handing out Bibles
in the fucking bullring with her cousins.
John, you don't have to do anything.
Lizzie will do it for you.
Then it'll all calm down,
and nobody will lose face.
I'll take his fucking face.
How about that?
-[door slams]
-John, do nothing... [sighing]
I believe you have a reservation
for a private room
in the name of Mr. Romanov.
[clicks tongue]
You work for Mr. Romanov?
-Yes.
-For his household or his office?
[sighing] Is there a problem?
I'm afraid without the presence
of the Duke Mikhail Michailovich
or Lady Lewington, we shall have to ask
for payment in advance.
Can I ask why?
Already, Mr. Romanov
has four outstanding bills with us.
One for accommodation
and three for dining.
And two banquets, which we wrote off.
We've been asked to be understanding
of our Russian friends by His Majesty.
-But it has been some time now...
-[thuds]
-May I ask your name, sir?
-Shelby.
Thomas Shelby, and in the future
I will be dining here quite a bit.
-Then I shall put you on our special list.
-You do that.
Here is a menu.
I recommend the teal and the pork.
Although your guest, I'm sure,
will order the caviar.
[Leon] Myself and my wife and my niece
traveled by train,
then coach, then on foot
through the Villa Ai-Todor in Crimea.
On that journey I lost a toe.
I don't know, I woke up one morning
and it was gone.
All of a sudden I saw a dog,
and it was eating it.
They said the British
had taken pity on us,
and we were taken aboard HMS Marlborough.
I immediately kissed the steel deck,
my lips froze to it.
And then, of course, I thanked God
and your King for saving us.
Though since then,
he has done nothing but humiliate me.
Who? God or the King?
Sometimes both, Mr. Shelby.
Mmm, so, you met my niece already?
Tatiana.
Are you in love with her yet, hmm?
You would be wise
not to love Russian women, you know.
Ah, better not speak of Russian women.
Mmm... That is the worst thing
about being here.
Russian women, they know how to hold it
and most important,
they know exactly when to let it go.
Your cock, I mean.
English women, they do not know so much.
You know?
Did he die well, the spy?
He begged for his life.
I heard you had your brother do it.
So you trust your family, like me,
like us, Mr. Shelby.
Let's talk about trust then, shall we?
You are not a direct relation
to the Romanovs, you are Georgian.
[glass shatters]
And the palace where you live
in Hampton Court
is, in fact, a grace and favor house
donated to you, rent-free
by the British Crown.
The maître d' here, tells me
that you are in some debt.
Both here and other places, I imagine.
See, I've been given ten,
but I've been promised 40.
Already, I have had to have a man killed,
that sort of work does not come cheap.
Do you understand?
Let me tell you something, Mr. Shelby.
Before we boarded the ship,
my niece sewed 16 diamonds
into her velvet dress,
and also she had two sapphires
in her intimate places.
My wife managed two sapphires
and five diamonds.
This is already for the killing of the spy
and a down payment on future services.
Now, tell me,
where do you keep these things?
In a bank?
How could we plead poverty
around London society
if we used banks, Mr. Shelby?
Well, you should know...
Hatton Gardens is not safe.
That's why we have our own treasury.
Very well, I shall have
my people check its veracity.
[Tommy grunts softly]
Before the revolution began,
we were soft and weak.
We made compromise.
But let me tell you.
We will never be soft and weak again.
Do you understand?
Good day, Mr. Shelby.
[man] This way, Mr. Changretta.
[man speaking Cantonese]
Just there, sir. There.
[yelling in Cantonese]
["Crying Lightning" playing]
[squelching]
[Angel] Are you going to kill me?
[John] Get fucking up.
Stay away from Lizzie!
[breathing heavily]
-[slicing]
-[Angel groaning]
[screaming]
By order of the Peaky fucking Blinders!
[Angel continues screaming]
[Tommy] Going to introduce me, Michael?
This is Charlotte Murray,
her father makes cars.
I really enjoyed your wedding, Mr. Shelby.
Polly said that you should call her.
There's been some trouble.
[Tommy] What trouble?
I'm guessing it's stuff
she doesn't like to tell me about.
[Tommy] Nice to meet you.
[chuckling]
[Arthur] All right, Finn,
thanks for coming. Fuck off.
Finn, you can stay.
[inhales sharply] Sit down, John.
Sit down.
John, you cut Angel Changretta.
-Even though Arthur told you to apologize.
-[John] Mmm-hmm.
-[Tommy] Polly told you to compromise.
You chose not to listen to Mr. Apologize
or Mrs. Compromise.
And now I have got an Italian
walking around my backyard
saying he's going to kill my brother.
So what do we do, John.
Do we apologize or do we compromise?
Oh, it was just something
John said as a joke.
Yeah, but he's your brother
as well, Arthur.
Yeah.
I know I didn't want to start a war
over something John said
without meaning it.
So, should he apologize in Italian
or in English?
Or should we ask them
which fucking language they prefer?
I'm not clear.
You said while this business was going on
in London, you wanted peace at home.
And the only way to guarantee peace
is by making the prospect of war
seem hopeless.
If you apologize once,
you do it again and again and again.
Like taking bricks out of the wall
of your fucking house.
Do you want
to bring the house down, Arthur?
-[Arthur grunts]
-If you're soft on rebellion, it'll grow.
Bloody "soft on rebellion."
You did the right thing, John.
Now, we go on the offensive.
We take two of the Changretta pubs,
and we take them tonight. That's it.
Oh! Right. For Christ's sake, why?
-Hey.
-Why?
[Tommy] Why? Because we fucking can.
Because we fucking can
and if we can, we do.
And if we lift our heel off their necks
now, they'll just come at us.
Remember these are the bastards
that wanted Danny Whizz-Bang dead.
You're getting soft, brother.
Soft and weak.
Save the Bible for Sundays, eh.
Finn?
I need to get to Hockley and then home.
It's been a long day.
You take the Wrexham,
you take the Five Bells.
You get them signed over to us
in the morning.
You make sure the coppers stay away.
Don't use the fucking phones, all right?
There's someone listening.
[Arthur] Well done.
[Polly slurping]
[ringing]
[conversing in Russian]
These are all to be typed tonight,
signed by you
and sent first post tomorrow.
This is to Duke Michail Michailovich
asking after his health
and suggesting
an alternative date for lunch.
This one is to Lady Lewington.
It is quite flirtatious
but I hear she is a whore
and will respond.
And this is to Mr. Shelby.
He has the effrontery
to check our sapphires,
we need proof
he has the material we require.
At a time of our choosing.
How much did you drink?
Wine, no vodka.
Hmm.
At the end of this business
you may have to kill Mr. Shelby yourself.
Can you do it?
Of course.
[wind howling]
[music playing over recorder]
Not hungry, Mrs. Shelby?
"Hungry"? Oh, no, sorry, Mary.
You'll ruin your eyes.
Tommy...
-[Tommy] Hello.
-Hello.
-Sit down.
-[clears throat]
-Guess.
-Guess what?
-He said yes.
-Who?
The leader of the Birmingham City Council
is going to attend the dinner.
-Everyone has said yes. Everyone.
-Ah. [clears throat]
I keep having to change the catering.
And my writing hand is almost falling off.
Oh, what are you writing for?
I bought you a typewriter.
[chuckles] You don't write letters
of a social occasion on a typewriter.
-Oh. Forgive me.
-[chuckles]
I have the drawings
of what they plan to do
with the grounds of the house.
There'll be an area
for the children to play. Look.
Mmm-hmm.
And the Birmingham Charity Commission
have agreed to set aside
their three rotten floorboards upstairs
and grant us the license within a month.
-You're not listening to me.
-Yes, I am. I am.
Do you think I'm becoming obsessed?
Yes.
Should I ask you how your day was,
like a good wife?
No.
I'm guessing that means your day
was not as successful as mine, hmm.
That all depends
on how you measure success.
See, personally,
I measure it in sapphires.
[chuckling] Oh!
-Sapphires. Mmm.
-Uh-huh.
Close your eyes.
[chuckles softly]
[whispers] Close your eyes.
All right, you can open 'em.
Where the hell did you get that?
It's beautiful.
You can wear it to the foundation dinner.
Don't you think it's a bit much
for a charity dinner?
Grace,
this is fucking Birmingham.
"Good taste" is for people
who can't afford sapphires.
[chuckling]
Oh, Mr. Shelby.
[thunder rumbling]
Did you wind the clock, Arthur?
We should go to bed.
[breathes deeply]
I need to...
I need to go out.
Some business I need to do.
"Business"?
But you only just got in.
I won't be long.
[Linda] It's 10:00.
It's pouring with rain.
I'll go...
I'll go and I'll come back.
Arthur.
Working in the dark is for the devil.
We said.
Start to do your work in the light.
Your own light.
Inside your head.
It's just paperwork.
I need you to clear your men
out of Nechells tonight.
I thought you boys were a bit grand
for this sort of thing these days.
Moss.
Mind you, I think Tommy enjoys the sport.
Something like that.
Good night, Arthur.
Night.
["I Might Be Wrong" playing]
[people screaming]
[John] Arthur, what are you doing?
Arthur?
We're going to the Garrison.
[Arthur] No. I'm going home, John.
[John] Go and fuck yourself, Arthur.
Yeah! Fuck off!
[Angel screaming]
[nurse shushing]
[conversing in Italian]
He will catch the train
from Naples to Paris
and then the boat train to London.
And he can be here by Sunday, yes?
[Angel continues screaming]
[gentle music playing]
-[Tommy] Come here, Charlie.
-[Grace] Charlie.
This big man and his brother
are going to make us a lot of money.
Or lose us a lot of money.
Who the hell cares
when they are such beautiful beasts, eh?
[Charlie mumbling]
[indistinct]
Go on.
[Esme moaning]
-[Tommy] You've got a house, John.
-[John] Oh, fuck.
Full of kids.
[Tommy] Well, you've got a maid
to look after the kids.
[John] Yeah, she listens.
[Tommy] Have you done the odds
for tomorrow?
Something urgent came up.
[John] They get worse
when they're pregnant, Tom.
John.
Esme, I need you to leave now.
Go out the back door,
and lock it after you.
Come on, I left the office.
There's two trucks full of coppers
out there, John.
Where the fuck is Arthur?
He goes home to the Madonna of Moseley
on the stroke of 5:00.
-[Esme] You need to talk to him, Tom.
-Esme, please, go. Now.
Please.
This is very fucking unusual.
So, call Moss.
They're from out of town.
London, by the looks of their boots...
-Since when are we scared of coppers, Tom?
-[gun clicking]
-Since things changed, John.
-[Esme screaming]
-[officer 1] Scotland Yard!
-[officer 2] Get down! Police!
-[officer 1] Go on!
-[Tommy] John!
[clamoring]
John! John, it's the Yard.
-Put it down.
-Putting it down. Putting it fucking down.
-Hands on your heads!
-Down on your knees! Now!
Let her fucking go!
She's fucking pregnant.
Leave her alone.
What the fuck is happening, Tom?
-[officer 1] Let's go.
-[Esme screams]
[Esme] Put me down!
-Tell Polly it's Russian business, John.
-All right.
Peaky fucking Blinders my arse.
-[Hughes] Is he afraid?
-No.
Go on.
Sit.
I'm talking to you, Mr. Shelby.
[scoffs]
So, the Odd Fellows want you to know
that any deviation
from your instructions
will have consequences.
What's your dog's name?
You visited your sister.
Eh? What's your name, boy?
[snarling]
Your sister is a potential
security breach.
She has connections
with the Bolsheviks in London
who have connections
with the Soviet Embassy.
I think I will just call your dog, "Boy."
You love your Boy, don't you?
Understand this.
You have the local police in your pocket,
we have Scotland Yard.
They do what we tell them
just as surely as this dog...
Let him off the leash.
Are you hearing me, Mr. Shelby?
I can charm dogs.
Gypsy witchcraft.
And those I can't charm,
I can kill with my own hands.
You learn it
when you have a dog on a boat.
They go fucking mad in tunnels.
I feel like I'm in a tunnel now.
You know that feeling,
when you have to kill or be killed?
Let the dog off the leash
and give the order you give in Gaelic...
Like I'm told you do
when someone displeases you
or someone reports you.
Visit your sister again,
and she will die crossing the road.
[in Gaelic]
Kill!
[in English] Then you say it.
If you wanted me dead,
I would be dead, wouldn't I?
[scoffs]
It's true.
It's true, we do need you alive.
But when you go home today, Mr. Shelby...
Be sure to check
under your little boy's pillow.
The tooth fairy has been.
We can reach anyone.
Anywhere.
[knocking]
[rock music playing]
[Charlie crying]
-Is everything all right?
-[panting] Yes.
Everything's fine. Everything's fine.
Yeah.
You promised, Tommy.
[breathing heavily]
I trust you.
-I trust you, Tommy.
-Yes.
[softly] He's fine. He's fine.
[Charlie crying]
Grace. Grace.
[whispering] We gotta go.
You're not one of those
Impressionists, are you?
They're all terribly political,
aren't they?
-And you're not?
-Goodness no.
The people I work for just
want me to paint what is there.
To me, politics is deliberately
making things better
for some people by deliberately
making them worse for others.
[footsteps approaching]
Well, I thought I might wear this.
Oh, God. It's too much.
I'll try something more simple.
No. Don't...
Suddenly, I feel incompetent.
I want the portrait to hang in the office,
so I want it to look formal.
[Ruben] It's not formal.
It's beautiful.
It was made in Paris.
It was stolen in Birmingham.
[chuckles nervously]
My mother stole it from a house
she was cleaning. 1901.
[Ruben] No. No.
It's yours. It belongs on you.
A woman of substance and class.
Believe me. I've painted many women
who don't belong
in their expensive dresses.
There'll be no charge.
Your normal rate.
-I insist.
-Hmm! There's a first.
-So, when shall we start?
-I've already started.
Come to my studio this evening.
-[Polly] Uh, I am busy this evening.
-Polly, invite him.
Invite me to what?
Ada, this is a professional transaction.
-Invite me to what?
-[Ada] Shelby Foundation dinner.
-Polly's going alone. You're invited...
-[Polly] Ada.
I'll come to your studio on Sunday.
And then we shall begin.
["This Is Love" playing]
♪ You're the only story
That I never told ♪
♪ You're my dirty little secret
Want to keep you so ♪
♪ You're the only story
That never been told ♪
♪ You're my dirty little secret
Want to keep you so ♪
♪ Come on out, come on over
Help me forget ♪
♪ Keep the walls from falling
As they're tumbling in ♪
♪ Come on out, come on over
Help me forget ♪
♪ Keep the walls from falling on me
Tumbling in ♪
♪ Keep the walls from falling
As they're tumbling in ♪
[indistinct conversations]
♪ This is love
This is love that I'm feeling ♪
♪ This is love... ♪
A woman of substance...
...and class.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Hello.
[woman] Hello, Polly.
[indistinct]
Tommy.
He's the leader
of the Birmingham City Council.
-Hello, Tommy.
-Hi, Danny.
[Daniel] How's the business?
[Tommy] All right, it's holding up,
holding up. How are you?
You know each other?
[Daniel chuckles] I have interests
in a steelworks in Cradley Heath.
Tommy helps me get my products
to the carmakers.
Congratulations, Mrs. Shelby,
on your wedding.
Thank you,
I'm surprised you weren't invited.
Now, how would that look, eh?
Oh, now, the party has really started.
Who are they?
[Daniel] Father John Hughes
from St. Mary's Boys Reformatory.
And with him is Mr. Patrick Jarvis, MP.
They are part of an organization
called the Economic League.
Did you invite them, Grace?
Their names sound familiar.
They were recommended by the Lord Mayor.
Oh. On your
"best people of the city" list, eh?
-[Grace] Do you know them?
-I'll introduce you, Tommy.
That's all right, Danny.
I'll introduce myself.
We appear to have taken you by surprise.
I have adjusted.
Since the socialists
got into Downing Street
we are all being followed.
We have to meet in places
where we'd meet anyway.
You should have stopped by Small Heath.
I could have given you
a more traditional welcome.
-They want to know about ammunition.
-[Patrick] And chains for the wheels.
When the White Guard
make their run for Tbilisi,
it will be over rough terrain.
[inhales sharply] The chains are suitable
for snow or wet ground.
They're already stowed on the vehicles.
There's a batch of weapons
set aside at the BSA,
which is bound for the Turkish army.
And how will you get it all aboard
the London train?
There will be a strike that night
across the city.
You will have to stop
the train twice. How?
Two drivers will join the strike
at different points.
Rather fun, getting the Communist unions
to help get weapons to the Whites.
[Tommy] Yes, rather fun, eh?
I am thinking ahead,
thinking of every possibility,
remembering everything that is happening.
[Patrick scoffs]
The Russians want to inspect the vehicles.
-I'll take photographs.
-[Patrick] Mmm-mmm.
The Duke has sent his niece, she's here.
Tomorrow you will take her to the factory
and show her.
No. Union conveners
are watching the factories.
Not possible.
Anything is possible, Mr. Shelby.
You will take her.
You will pick her up
from this hotel at 10:00.
Now, look, a priest with an empty glass.
Let's get back to the party.
You know, gentlemen, there is hell
and there is another place below hell.
I will remember everything...
and forget nothing.
[indistinct conversations]
[Grace] Tommy,
this is Duchess Tatiana Petrovna.
[clears throat]
Come on, Tommy, aren't you impressed
to meet a real duchess?
Well, I understand they charge a fee.
[scoffs] Mr. Shelby, you are very direct.
Too direct.
[Tatiana chuckles] But it's true.
I attend these things for the champagne.
And for the chance
to be treated like a duchess again.
You should have kissed my hand,
Mr. Shelby.
Forgive me.
She was asking about my sapphire.
-I thought I recognized it.
-She said it was Russian.
My husband has business in Russia.
Perhaps you know about it, Tatiana?
Well, tonight is not a night
for business, eh?
Is that why you were in the concert hall
for ten minutes?
I think people are ready
for dinner now, Grace.
No, no. I'm not done
pumping people for money.
What is "pump for money"?
It's what I do every day.
You know each other, do you?
You see, I am in charge
of compiling the list of guests,
but it's my husband
who seems to know all of them.
I hear he is very well connected.
And where does a duchess hear that?
In certain circles.
All right, enough. Ada.
Grace, there's a Lady Dowager
who wants to speak to you
about coffee mornings.
She mentioned a £2,000 cash donation.
Tatiana, you and I will speak later.
[Tatiana] I would like that.
Going to the factory tomorrow
is a mistake.
Nevertheless, we will go.
Also, my uncle ordered me to seduce you
to give us an advantage.
But with a beautiful wife like that
it will be difficult, no?
Tomorrow is a mistake.
Have you not heard?
We have no morals, we Russians.
And no fucking sense.
And no options.
I would fuck you for the cause.
What do you think of that?
I think you should not drink
vodka with champagne.
[Tatiana] Does your wife know
that the sapphire she is wearing
has been cursed by a Gypsy?
[chuckling]
What did you say?
Nothing on Earth would make me wear it.
Grace, listen to me. Look, I can explain.
-Go away.
-It's...
[MC] Ladies and gentlemen.
For once, you shouldn't have to explain.
The loyalty toast,
to His Majesty the King.
[all] To the King.
[MC] Dinner is served.
[Tommy] You look beautiful,
but you need to take this off.
Why? Because you think
it would look better on her?
Grace, look at me, fuck these people, eh.
Fuck 'em, I need you to be all right.
I need you, Grace. I need you.
Damn you, Tommy Shelby. [chuckles]
[chuckles]
-Shall we go inside?
-Yeah.
For Angel!
[gunshot]
[people screaming]
Get me a fucking ambulance now!
[theme song playing]
♪ On a gathering storm comes ♪
♪ A tall handsome man ♪
♪ In a dusty black coat with ♪
♪ A red right hand ♪